

Mobile: (202) 271-4027 E-mail: <u>lynguyen@gmail.com</u> Location: Washington, DC Website: www.ly-n.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/lynguyendc
Github: www.github.com/Ly900

ABOUT

I am a **persistent** and **curious** problem-solver who strives to gain expertise in any topics I encounter. I use my past skills and abilities as a teacher to share my knowledge and to meet goals with my team. I love to design, style, and to use JavaScript to make my pages come alive.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Full-time Web Development Immersive Student,

General Assembly, Washington, DC (10/15 - 1/16)

- Studied full-stack development in a 12-week program.
- Created independent and team projects:
 - TeacherFAMConnect: Ruby on Rails app that helps teachers manage student address book entries and communication with students' families.
 - ◆ TechWizMe: MEAN stack app that allows users to read and share popular technical interview questions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teacher,

Bancroft, Washington, DC (2008-2014),

- Demonstrate leadership abilities as Team Lead (2012-2013), and Teacher Lead (2013-2014)
 - Serve as liaison between administration and teachers.
 - Lead in team projects
 - Delegate tasks, assign and meet all deadlines
- Train staff on various school initiatives (application model, math problem-solving, whole brain learning, and responsive classroom).
- Generate interview questions and interviewed candidates for teaching positions and the assistant principal position.

School Without Walls at Francis Stevens, Washington, DC (2014-2015)

- Design unit plans, pacing guides, and lessons to meet District of Columbia Public Schools and Common Core State Standards.
- Problem-solve all issues in collaboration with students, parents, other paraprofessionals, and administrators.

SKILLS

TECH LANGUAGES

HTML
CSS/Bootstrap
JavaScript
SQL
Ruby
JSON
SASS

LIBRARIES/FRAMEWORKS

JQuery Sinatra Rails Express Angular Bootstrap

VERSION CONTROL/ DEPLOYMENT

Git Heroku

DATABASES

PostgreSQL MongoDB

METHODOLOGIES

ERDs Wireframing Ajax

OTHER LANGUAGES

Vietnamese Spanish

EDUCATION

University of Maryland at College Park (2004-2008)

- **☼** Bachelor of Science in Elementary Education
- Cumulative GPA of 3.4, Dean's list, Top 15% Praxis II scores
- Licensed to teach English as a Second Language